<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-08-29T17:23:11-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">The Normands Blog</title><subtitle>Food blog for the Normand family
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Sweet Potato Au Graten</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/soup/2017/08/29/sweet-potato-au-graten.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sweet Potato Au Graten" /><published>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/soup/2017/08/29/sweet-potato-au-graten</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/soup/2017/08/29/sweet-potato-au-graten.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 cups heavy cream
3 large potatoes or white sweet potatoes
2 cups grated Parmigiano-Reggiano
salt and pepper to taste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat the oven to 350°F. Grease a baking dish with butter. Mix cream, salt, and pepper well. Alternate a layer of potato slices, cream, and parmesan, ending with cream and parmesan. Bake uncovered about an hour or until the potatoes are tender and the cheese turns golden.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ingredients 2 cups heavy cream 3 large potatoes or white sweet potatoes 2 cups grated Parmigiano-Reggiano salt and pepper to taste Directions Preheat the oven to 350°F. Grease a baking dish with butter. Mix cream, salt, and pepper well. Alternate a layer of potato slices, cream, and parmesan, ending with cream and parmesan. Bake uncovered about an hour or until the potatoes are tender and the cheese turns golden.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ratatouille</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sides/2017/08/29/ratatouille.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ratatouille" /><published>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sides/2017/08/29/ratatouille</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sides/2017/08/29/ratatouille.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;INGREDIENTS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3tablespoons olive oil
1 onion, thinly sliced
4 garlic cloves, peeled and sliced
1 small bay leaf
1 small eggplant, cut into 1/2-inch pieces (about 3 cups)
1 small zucchini, halved lengthwise and cut into thin slices
1 red bell pepper, cut into slivers
4 plum tomatoes, coarsely chopped (about 1 1/4 cups)
1teaspoon kosher salt
1/2cup shredded fresh basil leaves
freshly ground black pepper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;DIRECTIONS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over medium-low heat, add the oil to a large skillet with the onion, garlic, and bay leaf, stirring occasionally, until the onion has softened.
Add the eggplant and cook, stirring occasionally, for 8 minutes or until the eggplant has softened. Stir in the zucchini, red bell pepper, tomatoes, and salt, and cook over medium heat, stirring occasionally, for 5 to 7 minutes or until the vegetables are tender. Stir in the basil and few grinds of pepper to taste.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">INGREDIENTS 3tablespoons olive oil 1 onion, thinly sliced 4 garlic cloves, peeled and sliced 1 small bay leaf 1 small eggplant, cut into 1/2-inch pieces (about 3 cups) 1 small zucchini, halved lengthwise and cut into thin slices 1 red bell pepper, cut into slivers 4 plum tomatoes, coarsely chopped (about 1 1/4 cups) 1teaspoon kosher salt 1/2cup shredded fresh basil leaves freshly ground black pepper DIRECTIONS Over medium-low heat, add the oil to a large skillet with the onion, garlic, and bay leaf, stirring occasionally, until the onion has softened. Add the eggplant and cook, stirring occasionally, for 8 minutes or until the eggplant has softened. Stir in the zucchini, red bell pepper, tomatoes, and salt, and cook over medium heat, stirring occasionally, for 5 to 7 minutes or until the vegetables are tender. Stir in the basil and few grinds of pepper to taste.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Potato Leek Soup</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/soup/2017/08/29/potato-leek-soup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Potato Leek Soup" /><published>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/soup/2017/08/29/potato-leek-soup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/soup/2017/08/29/potato-leek-soup.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 tablespoons unsalted butter
2 large leeks
4-6 cloves garlic (peeled and smashed)
2 pounds gold potatoes, sliced 1/4”
8 cups chicken broth
2 bay leaves
1 sprig fresh thyme (plus more for garnish if desired)
1 cup heavy cream
salt and pepper to taste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chop leeks (whites and light greens only). Sweat leeks and garlic in butter in a large pot until softened. Add broth, herbs, and potatoes and bring to a boil. Cook until potatoes are soft. Turn down the heat and blend until smooth. Remove herbs and add heavy cream. Salt and pepper to taste. Simmer another 5 minutes stirring occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Omit cream and use vegetable broth for a vegetarian soup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garnish with chives, parsley, or green onion.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ingredients 4 tablespoons unsalted butter 2 large leeks 4-6 cloves garlic (peeled and smashed) 2 pounds gold potatoes, sliced 1/4” 8 cups chicken broth 2 bay leaves 1 sprig fresh thyme (plus more for garnish if desired) 1 cup heavy cream salt and pepper to taste Directions Chop leeks (whites and light greens only). Sweat leeks and garlic in butter in a large pot until softened. Add broth, herbs, and potatoes and bring to a boil. Cook until potatoes are soft. Turn down the heat and blend until smooth. Remove herbs and add heavy cream. Salt and pepper to taste. Simmer another 5 minutes stirring occasionally. Variations Omit cream and use vegetable broth for a vegetarian soup. Garnish with chives, parsley, or green onion.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pizza</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/italian/2017/08/29/pizza.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pizza" /><published>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/italian/2017/08/29/pizza</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/italian/2017/08/29/pizza.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven at 350°&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.5 cups almond flour
1 tsp salt
1/4 tsp baking soda&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix well&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1/2 cup shredded cheese (harder is better)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a bite yourself because cheese. Shred. Mix well with dry mixture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 small eggs
1.5 tbsp oil&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix well then mix with dry ingredients until cohesive. Add a bit more almond flour if it is too wet, about 1/8 of a cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press under two pieces of parchment paper and roll out as thin as possible while keeping it even and not lumpy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peel top parchment paper off. Slide onto cookie sheet and bake to 10-12 until begins to turn golden around the edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pull out of oven and add ingredients and put it back in another 10-12 minutes or until it looks like pizza.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ingredients Preheat oven at 350° 1.5 cups almond flour 1 tsp salt 1/4 tsp baking soda Mix well 1/2 cup shredded cheese (harder is better) Take a bite yourself because cheese. Shred. Mix well with dry mixture. 2 small eggs 1.5 tbsp oil Directions Mix well then mix with dry ingredients until cohesive. Add a bit more almond flour if it is too wet, about 1/8 of a cup. Press under two pieces of parchment paper and roll out as thin as possible while keeping it even and not lumpy. Peel top parchment paper off. Slide onto cookie sheet and bake to 10-12 until begins to turn golden around the edges. Pull out of oven and add ingredients and put it back in another 10-12 minutes or until it looks like pizza.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pickles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/snacks/2017/08/29/pickles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pickles" /><published>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/snacks/2017/08/29/pickles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/snacks/2017/08/29/pickles.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 1/4 cup vinegar (can just be a heaping cup)
1 cup water
1 tsp pickling salt
1 garlic clove
1 bay leaf
Whatever you want to pickle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boil the vinegar, water, and salt. Put the bay leaf, garlic, and pickle in a thick glass jar. Once the vinegar mixture is a roaring boil, pour into jar. Do not pack pickles too tightly. Thicker items such as carrots or green beans may need to be parboiled in the vinegar mixture briefly to get desired texture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pickles should stay crisp. Pickles that start wilting or have a slimy appearance should be discarded. Keeps about a week.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ingredients</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Frying with Cornmeal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sides/2017/08/29/frying-with-cornmeal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Frying with Cornmeal" /><published>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sides/2017/08/29/frying-with-cornmeal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sides/2017/08/29/frying-with-cornmeal.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 cup cornmeal
1 cup 1to1 flour
1 cup rice flour
3 large eggs
1 tablespoon salt
something to fry
oil to fry it in (high temperature oil like canola, peanut, corn, no olive oil)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beat the egg. Mix the flours and salt together. Dip what you want to fry into the egg mixture and press into the cornmeal. The idea is to get a goopy mess of eggs and press a lot of cornmeal mixture into it so it gets soaked. Refrigerate or freeze until the dough mixture becomes cohesive. The food should not need to fully freeze, but freezing is okay as long as internal temperature for meats is taken into consideration. Before frying, check that the oil you are using has a smoke point of at least 400F. Heat the oil to exactly 375F. A high sided small pot works well. The oil should not be smoking but should shimmer. Drop the items to fry cafefully into the oil but do not crowd the pan. Flip when one side starts to look crispy. If the oil starts to smoke from breading debris, replace the oil or skim large chunks out. Remove fried food once the breading is light golden to a wire rack. Serve with your favorite sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: For meats such as chicken and fish, use a thermometer to ensure the internal temperature is at least 150F. This is especially important when frying frozen food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The starches in the breading create a barrier around the item being fried, causing it to stay juicy, while the water in the breading boils and pushes the oil away. Because of this, deep frying is a dry cooking technique. By using egg, we can help the starch by making the breading cohesive without making it gummy like starch is known for. We press the breading against a liberal amount of egg wash and let it sit so the egg has time to soak, otherwise the breading falls right off and causes the oil to smoke and food to taste burnt. Refrigerating or freezing helps the egg to set with the breading and freezing lets us prep fried foods in advance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ingredients 1 cup cornmeal 1 cup 1to1 flour 1 cup rice flour 3 large eggs 1 tablespoon salt something to fry oil to fry it in (high temperature oil like canola, peanut, corn, no olive oil) Directions Beat the egg. Mix the flours and salt together. Dip what you want to fry into the egg mixture and press into the cornmeal. The idea is to get a goopy mess of eggs and press a lot of cornmeal mixture into it so it gets soaked. Refrigerate or freeze until the dough mixture becomes cohesive. The food should not need to fully freeze, but freezing is okay as long as internal temperature for meats is taken into consideration. Before frying, check that the oil you are using has a smoke point of at least 400F. Heat the oil to exactly 375F. A high sided small pot works well. The oil should not be smoking but should shimmer. Drop the items to fry cafefully into the oil but do not crowd the pan. Flip when one side starts to look crispy. If the oil starts to smoke from breading debris, replace the oil or skim large chunks out. Remove fried food once the breading is light golden to a wire rack. Serve with your favorite sauce. Note: For meats such as chicken and fish, use a thermometer to ensure the internal temperature is at least 150F. This is especially important when frying frozen food. Explanation The starches in the breading create a barrier around the item being fried, causing it to stay juicy, while the water in the breading boils and pushes the oil away. Because of this, deep frying is a dry cooking technique. By using egg, we can help the starch by making the breading cohesive without making it gummy like starch is known for. We press the breading against a liberal amount of egg wash and let it sit so the egg has time to soak, otherwise the breading falls right off and causes the oil to smoke and food to taste burnt. Refrigerating or freezing helps the egg to set with the breading and freezing lets us prep fried foods in advance.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Eggplant Parmesan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/italian/2017/08/29/eggplant-parmesan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eggplant Parmesan" /><published>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/italian/2017/08/29/eggplant-parmesan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/italian/2017/08/29/eggplant-parmesan.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 servings&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;About an hour total, 30 minutes prep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 eggplants
One 20oz can of  tomato sauce
One 8oz can of tomato paste
Salt, pepper, basil, oregano, garlic, other Bolognese seasonings
1/2-1lb sausage (optional)
8oz mozzarella
6oz shredded parmesan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eggplant&quot;&gt;Eggplant&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slice 2 eggplants into 1” or thinner slices. Salt both sides on a wire rack and leave for 8 minutes. Rinse and wring the eggplant out. Optionally, fry in a hot skillet on each side briefly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sauce&quot;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One 20oz can of tomato sauce and one 8oz of paste
Salt, pepper, basil, oregano, garlic, other seasoning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simmer sauce and reduce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;casserole&quot;&gt;Casserole&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brown some sausage. Layer eggplant, sausage, tomato sauce, and top with cheese. Cook on 350° for 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ingredients 6 servings About an hour total, 30 minutes prep 2 eggplants One 20oz can of tomato sauce One 8oz can of tomato paste Salt, pepper, basil, oregano, garlic, other Bolognese seasonings 1/2-1lb sausage (optional) 8oz mozzarella 6oz shredded parmesan Directions Eggplant Slice 2 eggplants into 1” or thinner slices. Salt both sides on a wire rack and leave for 8 minutes. Rinse and wring the eggplant out. Optionally, fry in a hot skillet on each side briefly. Sauce One 20oz can of tomato sauce and one 8oz of paste Salt, pepper, basil, oregano, garlic, other seasoning Simmer sauce and reduce Casserole Brown some sausage. Layer eggplant, sausage, tomato sauce, and top with cheese. Cook on 350° for 30 minutes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chili</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/american/2017/08/29/chili.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chili" /><published>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/american/2017/08/29/chili</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/american/2017/08/29/chili.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;chili-recipe&quot;&gt;Chili Recipe&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4lb ground beef
1/4 onion
1 tablespoon salt
2tbsp cumin
2tbsp oregano
2 guajillo
1 pastillo
1 ancho
2 chipotle (either kind)
1 habanero (for spicy)
1/4 cup masa harina (corn dough flour)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grill onions on stove in cast iron pan so they dehydrate slightly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seed and soak chilis in hot water. Add seasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When onions are done, move to chili mixture. Blend chili mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lightly salt and brown meat in cast iron. Drain meat and add with masa to pot and mix well.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I put the masa in the pot and brown the meat in 1lb batches and move to pot as it’s ready.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add chili seasoning. Add enough water to make it sloshy. Slow cook (while adding water as needed) until it looks like chili, usually four to ∞ hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Chili Recipe Ingredients 4lb ground beef 1/4 onion 1 tablespoon salt 2tbsp cumin 2tbsp oregano 2 guajillo 1 pastillo 1 ancho 2 chipotle (either kind) 1 habanero (for spicy) 1/4 cup masa harina (corn dough flour) Directions Grill onions on stove in cast iron pan so they dehydrate slightly. Seed and soak chilis in hot water. Add seasoning. When onions are done, move to chili mixture. Blend chili mixture. Lightly salt and brown meat in cast iron. Drain meat and add with masa to pot and mix well. I put the masa in the pot and brown the meat in 1lb batches and move to pot as it’s ready. Add chili seasoning. Add enough water to make it sloshy. Slow cook (while adding water as needed) until it looks like chili, usually four to ∞ hours.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zucchini Lasagna</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/italian/2017/07/16/zucchini-lasagna.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zucchini Lasagna" /><published>2017-07-16T23:34:12-05:00</published><updated>2017-07-16T23:34:12-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/italian/2017/07/16/zucchini-lasagna</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/italian/2017/07/16/zucchini-lasagna.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4-6 small yellow squash or zucchini, try to get with small seeds
1lb Ricotta
1/2lb Mozerella
1 cup Parmesan
1 egg
Spaghetti sauce ingredients
1 1/2lb meat (optional, beef, lamb, and pork work well)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients-1&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4-6 small yellow squash or zucchini, try to get with small seeds
1lb Ricotta
1/2lb Mozerella
1 cup Parmesan
1 egg
1 regular can tomato sauce
1 8oz can tomato paste
4 cloves garlic
1 shallot (optional)
Fennel
Basil and oregano (fresh preferred, dried works)
1 1/2lb meat (optional, beef, lamb, and pork work well)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;directions-1&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disgorge squash in 1/4” slices, easy to sandwich between two cutting boards and towels to squeeze the moisture out. Cook some thich spaghetti sauce with some tomato paste (one can of each). If using meat, brown 1.5lb of meat first then cook the sauce in. Mix ricotta, egg, parmesan, and some parsley flakes together. Alternate layering squash slices, cheese mix, mozerella, sauce, then top final layer lightly with sauce and parmesan. Bake covered at 350F for 35 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;variations&quot;&gt;Variations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roll zucchini around filling. See http://reciperunner.com/zucchini-lasagna-rolls/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thin slice raw white sweet potato for noodles (might need to pre-cook or bake lasagna for an additional 15 minutes)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ingredients</summary></entry></feed>