<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>relax&#43;dine</title>
    <link>http://www.relaxanddine.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on relax&#43;dine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 11:46:57 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.relaxanddine.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Biscuits</title>
      <link>http://www.relaxanddine.com/baking/biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 11:46:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.relaxanddine.com/baking/biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 cup gf flour with xantham gum (1to1 or Cup4Cup) 1 cup super fine white rice flour 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp salt 4 tsp tbsp baking powder 1&amp;frasl;4 tsp baking soda 8 tbsp (1 stick) frozen butter About 1 cup buttermilk (enough to make it thoroughly moist but not tacky)
Directions Preheat 450F. Thoroughly mix dry ingredients. Shred frozen butter into dry and mix lightly. Incorporate in the buttermilk carefully, enough for the dry to soak up the buttermilk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pot Roast</title>
      <link>http://www.relaxanddine.com/cooking/pot-roast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 21:36:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.relaxanddine.com/cooking/pot-roast/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 chuck roast, about 3-4lb 1 whole onion 4 large carrots 2 parsnips 4 cloves garlic A whole savoy cabbage
1 tbsp thyme 1 tbsp rosemary 1 tbsp sweet paprika 1 tbsp powdered garlic 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp ground mustard 1 tbsp salt Several grinds of black pepper A couple dashes of red wine vinegar A splash of a good red wine, if available
Directions Sear the roast well in a cast iron skillet to develop a good brown crust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meatballs</title>
      <link>http://www.relaxanddine.com/components/meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 22:00:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.relaxanddine.com/components/meatballs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 2 lb ground beef or lamb, or 50&amp;frasl;50 of both 1 lb ground pork 1 slice of bread, very stale, shredded 1 large egg 2 tbsp each of: oregano sage garlic powder onion powder salt pepper
Directions Preheat oven to 425F. Shred the stale bred with a fine grater, to crumbs. Mix with seasoning and egg. Mix very well with the ground meat. Use a disher appropriate to the size of desired meatball to portion out each meatball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salsbury Steak</title>
      <link>http://www.relaxanddine.com/cooking/salsbury-steak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 22:00:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.relaxanddine.com/cooking/salsbury-steak/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1lb ground beef, good quality 3 tbsp butter 1&amp;frasl;2 sweet onion (or a whole one, why not? Why&amp;hellip; not) 2 cups beef or lamb broth A few dashes of worchester 1 tsp thyme 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp marjoram 1 tbsp paprika 1 tsp powdered garlic A couple dashes of apple cider vinegar 3 mini bella mushrooms
Directions Carmelize most of the onion, saving a couple tablespoons finely diced for the meat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>